exoscale.com 2019-12-08

# Privacy License Agreement | Exoscale European Cloud

## In short

Exoscale only collects and information you choose to give us, and processes it with your consent or on legal basis. We collect as little personal information as we can to allow us to provide our services. Personal information is not sold to third parties and is used and processed as described on this page.

We comply with the EU’s Privacy Sheld framework and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). We provide the same level of privacy protection regardless of your country of origin or location.

## Information collected by Exoscale

### Information from website browsers

If you’re browsing Exoscale websites, we rely on cookies, server logs and web analytics providers to automatically collect basic information about the visitor.

This information includes the browser type, operating system, language preferrence, referring site, and the date and time of each request. We also collect potentially personally-identifying information such as IP addresses.

### Information from users with Exoscale accounts

On account creation, we ask for the following information:

  * Email address
  * Password
  * Full name and/or company name
  * Billing address

We also collect personal information from you when you subscribe to our newsletters. If you contact us from our website’s contact form or our support platform, we keep a copy of your communications with us. We also keep a copy of all communication we send you that is related to the providing of our services.

## Use of collected information

We use the personal information we collect from you for the following purposes:

  * To deal with your requests
  * To provide you with information and access to resources that you have requested from us
  * To provide you with technical support
  * To improve our website’s performance and efficiency in assisting you with the use of our products
  * For intrusion and misuse detection and securing access to our systems as well as enforcing our Terms of Service
  * To improve our efficiency with customer service, content and functionality of our offering, to better understand our users’s needs and for general business management.
  * To send important email notifications related to your use of the service.
  * When you have allowed us to do so, to send occasional newsletter and marketing campaigns about our services. You can unsubscribe from these at any time using the link provided in the message.

## Protection of information

Safe handling of your personal information when it’s entered, submitted or accessed is ensured by the use of TLS for all communications over the network.

Furthermore, we rely on PCI-compliant payment providers and do not store financial or credit card information on our servers. Identification of your account between Exoscale and the credit card processor is done through an anonymized token that we exchange in an encrypted way.

Our data isn’t encrypted at-rest, however we control control access to our datacenter locations with physical and network security.

## Cookies and tracking

We use cookies and affiliated technologies such as `localStorage` to keep you logged in on our web properties and remembering your preferences.

Our web analytics provider(s) also use cookies as a tracking mechanism. We only enable analytics on our public properties and within our customer onboarding process to improve our performance in these areas.

The following third parties are instead used to set cookies and tracking on `exoscale.com` websites upon consent:

3rd Party | Purpose  
---|---  
Facebook | Advertising optimization  
Google | Analytics, Advertising optimization  
Linkedin | Advertising optimization  
Twitter | Content offering, Advertising optimization  
Zoho PageSense | Heatmaps, A/B testing  
Beamer | Changelog notifications, Analytics  
  
No 3rd party tracking or analytics cookie is allowed on `portal.exoscale.com`, granting you privacy protection during the use of the application.

## Data processors

Exoscale may rely on third-party subprocessor(s) to carry out specific processing activities on behalf of the Client throughout its providing of the Services. A list of subprocessors is available in the following table:

Name of data processor | Purpose | Location  
---|---|---  
(currently no third-party processor) |  |   
  
## Third-party providers

Exoscale relies on third-party providers to fullfill its services. Exoscale hence forwards data about its Clients to these providers. Under no circumstances is data uploaded by Clients to Exoscale services transferred to these providers.

Name of provider | Purpose | Location  
---|---|---  
Bexio | Accounting | Switzerland  
Postfinance | Payment Service Provider | Switzerland  
PayPal | Payment Service Provider | United States  
Aduno | Credit card processor | Switzerland  
Google Analytics | Web analytics | United States  
Twitter | Web analytics | United States  
Zoho | A/B testing | India  
Mailchimp | Newsletters and marketing campaigns | United States  
A1 Digital International | Business intelligence | Austria  
Amazon Web Services | Data archival | United States  
Joincube (aka. Beamer) | Changelog user notifications | United States  
  
## Children under 16

If you are a child under the age of 16, you may not have an Exoscale account. Exoscale does not collect information about users’ age, but if we learn that you are a user who is under the age of 16, we will terminate your account.

## Exercise of rights

As an Exoscale Client, you are entitled to exercising the following rights with regard to the personal data Exoscale holds about you:

  * Right of information
  * Right of access
  * Right to rectification
  * Right to erasure
  * Right to restriction of processing
  * Right to data portability
  * Right to object to processing
  * Right to not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing.

Exercise-of-rights enquiries should be addressed by emailing privacy@exoscale.ch to be handled by the Exoscale team under supervision of the Exoscale Data Privacy Officer.
